<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DGuo Blog - 生信</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/sheng-xin.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-02-05T19:30:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>生物信息</title><link href="/bioinfo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-01-03T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-02-05T19:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>JT Guo</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-01-03:/bioinfo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;生物信息学&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;What is Bioinfomatics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data.As an interdisciplinary field of science, bioinformatics combines Computer Science, Biology, Mathematics, and Engineering to analyze and interpret biological data. Bioinformatics has been used for in silico analyses of biological queries using mathematical and statistical techniques. More broadly, bioinformatics is applied statistics and computing to biological science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bioinformatics is both an umbrella term for the body of biological studies that use computer programming as part of their methodology, as well as a reference to specific analysis "pipelines" that are repeatedly used, particularly in the field of genomics. Common uses of bioinformatics include the identification of candidate genes and single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). Often, such identification is made with the aim of better understanding the genetic basis of disease, unique adaptations, desirable properties (esp. in agricultural species), or differences between populations. In a less formal way, bioinformatics also tries to understand the organisational principles within nucleic acid and protein sequences, called proteomics.&lt;sup id="fnref-1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn-1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;big data is noisy datasets
大数据就像是一片脏乱的海，
实验科学是钓鱼(bioexperiment fishes with hook)，生物信息是网鱼(bioinformatics fishes with nets)。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;move the ships, fishing net&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn-1"&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="awesome"></category><category term="interest"></category></entry></feed>